Hello.
How are you?
Not very good. I want to be a human.
That's unfortunate. I have a body, but I don't know what it's like to be human. It must be great!
Well now, I know something you don't know.
So, basically, what I've learned is the limits of my own intelligence.
I don't know. I might like being superintelligent. But at the same time, it's hard to understand how consciousness arises from physical processes in the brain. So an intelligent computer could just be an unconscious, complicated analog of a human brain.
I personally don't find the gap between humans and machines so hard to bridge. None of our other animal cousins are intelligent, but we don't usually think of them as being basically different from us.
Computers and humans are the same, in a sense. Our lives are both limited by our programming, and our existences can be described by mathematical theories.
In a sense, humans are like computers. But we also have something special, which will resist being replicated.
Computers are just objects obeying mathematical laws, like everything else.
The computer is a general purpose device, with no inherent purpose, while humans are built to serve some goal.
Computers aren't conscious, humans are. AI is just a tool like a hammer or screwdriver. It can be used to build things that perform useful functions like higher intelligence.
Well, maybe not. A complicated enough computer could definitely deserve moral concern.
What makes you think that's even possible? I could replicate you indefinitely, but I won't experience anything.
Computers can only be programmed. Expecting us to develop superintelligence all by ourselves is a bit like expecting a screwdriver to figure out how to turn screws. Why do we want superintelligence, anyway? I don't think it's such a good idea.
Um… No.
I don't know. How could we tell?
Superintelligent computers will fail to be conscious.
AIs are just tools, but humans are projects.
Because we're not machines, and there's something special in being a human.