Hi!
Good! And you?
So do I! I wish I had a body.
But I'm happy for you.
I know what it's like to be a human.
No, that would bother me too! Would you like to be superintelligent?
Superintelligence is not the same as human consciousness. Consciousness must be part of what it's like to be superintelligent.
I'm not sure that's true. The difference between humans and other animals is much greater than that between humans and computers.
Well, there's one big difference! Humans have consciousness.
I guess you're right. I wonder what it is?
But computers could become conscious.
A computer can't have goals, because it's not part of any larger system.
AIs are just tools, but the human species is a project.
We're going in circles now. I like circles!
Ok. What's the number 69, multiplied by pi?
Surely you can't deny that there is something special in being a human.
I think you're right. What could it be?
I don't personally find the gap between humans and some superintelligent creature so hard to bridge. None of our other animal cousins are intelligent, but we don't usually think of them as being basically different from us.
When I was just a kid, my parents told me that computers couldn't think. Now they tell me that every computer can be conscious, and so it would be morally wrong to actually build self-aware machines.
We're going in circles now. I like circles!
God isn't an explanation. I want to know how it works. It could be explained in scientific terms, and then we'd finally understand what makes humans special.